YOUHAN GUAN

23 Hollywood Ave, Toronto, M2N 7L8

Phone: 416-566-0128 — Email: <u>youhan.guan@gmail.com</u> http://youhanguan.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

Youhan Guan is a creative coder, interaction designer and UI/UX designer exploring in various digital media fields; familiar with the major aspects of the field and further specializing in user interface / experience design, VR/AR development and interactive installations / performance development.

EDUCATION

Specialized Honour B.A. in Digital Media Anticipated Completion June 2016 Lassonde School of Engineering, York University, Toronto, ON, Canada

WORK EXPERIENCE

User Interface Design Intern

June 2014 - August 2015

IBM Canada, Toronto, Ontario

- Designed the wireframe and visual mock-ups of cloud applications for multiple products, such as IBM Watson and Incentive Compensation Management Desktop/Web.
- Designed the wireframe and visual of a multi-platform application for demo in IBM Vision 2015.
- Created series of user interface visual elements details for various applications.

Web Designer and Developer

May 2014 - August 2014

Aoyee International, Toronto, Ontario

- Designed and constructed firm's official site based on the Drupal system within a team.
- Worked as the main graphic designer of Hainan Airline 20th Anniversary Celebration.
- Designed the logo for Canada-China Business Engagement Association.

PROJECTS AND COLLABORATION

Web / Mobile Application Design and Development:

Food R Us December 2015

- Designed and developed an e-commerce website using APACHE Server based on MVC structure, coded in Java. Featuring full functionality of B2C online-shopping, analysis, user authentication, and a B2C-B2B middleware providing purchase order report files to food supplier.
- Rank 1st place in the course EECS 4413, Building eCommerce Systems.

PlantPot November 2015

- Designed and developed the mobile end of an Internet of Things (IoT) project featuring a fully automatic gardening system, developed based on Intel Edison and analytics using IBM Bluemix platform.
- Awarded the 3rd place of the Intel IoT Roadshow 2015 at Toronto.

Blink November 2015

- A mixed reality game designed and developed for Leap Motion 3D Jam using Leap Motion gesture sensor and Oculus rift head mounted display, featuring switching between VR and AR views and a gesture controlled AR UI interface.
- Showcased in LevelUp showcase Toronto, 2016

Encounter January – April 2016

 Encounter is an interactive installation which explores the coexistence of human and a virtual artificial life ecosystem through Spacital Augmented Reality and Tangible Augmented Reality means.

• A spatial co-located 3D graphics data visualization and query system is developed using Unity and Vuforia SDK, for both Android and ios devices.

For digital media projects, please visit: http://youhanguan.com

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES

Design Director 2013 – 2015

York University Chinese Students and Scholars Association (YUCSSA)

- Contributed design skills for each events.
- Tasks allocation and scheduling. Holds workshops and to tutor Adobe Photoshop.

4th Year Programming Tutor

2015

Digital Media Student Association (DMSA) at York University

Helping and tutoring students in Digital Media program with courses involving coding in Java.

Science Tutor September 2012 – Present

NATS-aid at York University

- Face-to-face instructions and tutoring with students from Nature Science courses.
- Online instructions using multiple instant messaging tools, social media and emails.

ACHIVEMENTS / AWARDS

- Dean's Honour Roll since 2014
- Projects been exhibited and presented in Digital Media Showcase (2012 -2016), I/O Exhibition of Interactive Art (2013), Surface Normal (2014), LevelUp Showcase Toronto at Design Exchange (2015), Pan Am / Parapan Am Games at York (2015), ISO: Student Night at The Power Plant (2015), Computational Beauty at Interaccess (2016).
- 3rd Place in Intel IoT Roadshow Toronto (2015).
- Golden Key International Honour Society member since 2015.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems

Experience using Windows-, Mac- and UNIX- based systems.

Design Skills

Professional in Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, AfterEffects, Premiere.

Programming Languages

Java, JavaScript, HTML, HTML5, CSS, C#, MIPS Assembler, Unix Shell Scripts

IBM DB2 database management system and programming SQL.

Other Skills

Installations using Arduino, Intel Edison.

Professional in Unity3D, 3DsMax, Google SketchUp, Lotus

LANGUAGES

Mandarin and English – both fluent, advanced reading and writing.